Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/neillukowski (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Office
Python (Programming Language)
Computer-Aided Design (CAD)

Neil Lukowski

Controls Engineer at Corning Optical Communications Hickory, North Carolina, United States

Summary

I have always loved figuring out how the technology of the modern world works and finding ways to improve the human experience through its application. My passion for learning and diving deep into the process of discovery has never diminished. I want to collaborate with the best minds to solve challenging problems and design the future.

My background is a bit different from a typical engineering graduate. I came to university with 5 years of professional leadership experience and I have spent my time on campus honing those skills. I have guided the campus chapter of IEEE to new successes by focusing on mentorship and professional training. The 2020/2021 move to online education was a challenge, but with the help of my team of officers we were able to offer training on microcontrollers, programming, resume building, and professional presentations. I was even able to teach a lesson based on my Statistical Machine Learning course, exposing other students to a fascinating and growing field. Perhaps my greatest accomplishment was seeing one of my officers take the leadership mantle and continue to execute on the organizational structure I had implemented, growing the chapter and reaching new levels of success.

I am eager to join a team of professionals and work hard to help overcome exceptional challenges. I will learn quickly, grow my abilities, and continue to make it my life's mission to improve the lives of as many as I am able.

Experience

Corning Incorporated
Controls Engineer
May 2022 - Present (1 year)
Hickory, North Carolina, United States

As a controls engineer, I analyze user requirements, process design, and mechanical equipment design to create controls architecture for automated systems. I collaborate with engineers and technicians to define and perform experiments to develop process technologies and solutions.

College of Engineering & Technology at Western Carolina University

Design Engineer I Intern

May 2020 - April 2022 (2 years)

Cullowhee, North Carolina, United States

Sole electrical engineer on a team of 8 interns who were tasked with developing and testing solutions for Rapid Center clients.

Programmed the movement of a linear actuator using a microcontroller and two limit switches.

Researched methods for driving piezoelectric ceramics in the 2-8 MHz range.

Assembled a Hartley Oscillator capable of generating selected frequencies.

Built an arbitrary wave generator to generate all desired frequencies.

Guided a team of 7 interns that designed and fabricated an award coin for a VA hospital using 3D modeling and FDM printing.

Taught 4 interns programming fundamentals, basic electronics, professionalism, and financial management

BB&T

4 years 7 months

Branch Banker

March 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Hickory/Lenoir, North Carolina Area

Discovered deposit, credit, and loan opportunities to deepen client relationship with bank

Provided customer service and problem resolution while maintaining safe cash handling procedures

Bank Teller

January 2014 - March 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Newport News, Virginia, United States

Managed the vault and kept cash within safety limits which resulted in compliance audits being 100%

Devised plan to call 10 clients a day to generate new loan opportunities and grow deposit accounts

Faith FWB Church Associate Pastor June 2012 - December 2017 (5 years 7 months) Carrollton, Virginia, United States

Conducted public services, wrote training material for different age groups, and personally mentored 5 teens

Spearheaded the planning and fundraising of \$3000 for 10 young people to attend summer camp

Education

Western Carolina University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Electrical Engineering · (2018 - 2022)

Southeastern Free Will Baptist College
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Pastoral Studies/Counseling · (2007 - 2010)

Cleveland Community College
Associate of Science - AS, Physical Sciences · (2004 - 2007)